New York Statewide Senior Action Council Records
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Correspondence, 1982-1984; nam_apap111-2; 0.17 cubic ft.
  These records include the correspondence sent and received by Michael Burgess, Executive Director of NYSSAC during this period. Documents include personal letters, intra-organization correspondence, and correspondence with notables such as State Senator Hugh Farley; Director of State Executive Services, Tonio Burgos; Assembly Speaker Stanley Fink; Assemblyman Paul Harenberg; Executive Deputy Secretary of State, James N. Baldwin; and cartoons and letters by local newspaper cartoonist, Charles Ferraro. The series also holds responses to the Public Services Commission's Energy Conservation Survey and correspondence on the grassroots promotional campaign, Savingpower, supporting the Home Insulation and Energy Conservation Act (HIECA).
  - Correspondence, Outgoing, 1982-1983; nam_apap111-2_1 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, Outgoing, 1984; nam_apap111-2_2 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, Received, 1982-1983; nam_apap111-2_3 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence, Received, 1984; nam_apap111-2_4 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Draft Correspondence to Politicians, 1984; nam_apap111-2_5 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Intra-NYSSAC, 1982-1983; nam_apap111-2_6 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Public Service Commission Energy Conservation Survey, 1984; nam_apap111-2_7 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Public Service Commission Program, 1984; nam_apap111-2_8 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Publications, 1977-1981; 1983-2000; nam_apap111-3; 1.5 cubic ft.
  These records contain informational material published by the New York StateWide Senior Action Council in the form of guides, booklets and ephemera. Topics such as community services for senior citizens, Medicare, and consumer issues are addressed. The series includes, NYSSAC's Annual Report for 2000, a position paper against HEAP transfer and, notably, both the Sentinel newsletter (1992-1996) and the Senior Action newspaper (1977-1981, 1983-1994, 1996-2000).
  - Annual Report, 2000; nam_apap111-3_1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bumper Stickers/Membership Cards, Undated; nam_apap111-3_2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Guide to Senior Programs, 1999; nam_apap111-3_3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Guide to Senior Programs, 2000-2001; nam_apap111-3_4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Home Energy Audit Request Slip, 1984; nam_apap111-3_5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Informational Brochures, Undated; nam_apap111-3_6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lifetime Legislative Award Honoring Paul Harenberg, 1997; nam_apap111-3_7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - NYSSAC, Brochure and Priorities, 1985-1986; nam_apap111-3_8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Patients' Rights Alert, 1991; nam_apap111-3_9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Position Paper Against HEAP Transfer, 1984; nam_apap111-3_10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Proposed Patients' Bill of Rights, Media Release, Undated; nam_apap111-3_11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Public Service Commission Utility Rates Mailings, 1984; nam_apap111-3_12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Originals, nam_apap111-3.13
    - StateWide Sentinel, Monthly Newsletter, 1992 September-1992 December; nam_apap111-3.13_1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - StateWide Sentinel, Monthly Newsletter, 1993; nam_apap111-3.13_2 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Lacking issues for March, July, September.
    - StateWide Sentinel, Monthly Newsletter, 1994; nam_apap111-3.13_3 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Lacking issue November-December.
    - StateWide Sentinel, Monthly Newsletter, 1995; nam_apap111-3.13_4 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Lacking issue January-February.
    - StateWide Sentinel, Monthly Newsletter, 1996; nam_apap111-3.13_5 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Lacking issues for February, July, December.
  - Preservation Photocopies, nam_apap111-3.14
    - Senior Action, January/April, May/August, 1977; nam_apap111-3.14_1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Senior Action, January/March, September-December, 1978; nam_apap111-3.14_2 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Senior Action, 1979; nam_apap111-3.14_3 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Senior Action, January, April-June, October, 1980; nam_apap111-3.14_4 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Senior Action, January-August, 1981; nam_apap111-3.14_5 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Senior Action, 1983; nam_apap111-3.14_6 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Senior Action, 1984; nam_apap111-3.14_7 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Senior Action, 1985; nam_apap111-3.14_8 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Senior Action, 1986; nam_apap111-3.14_9 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Senior Action, 1987; nam_apap111-3.14_10 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Senior Action, 1988; nam_apap111-3.14_11 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Senior Action, 1989; nam_apap111-3.14_12 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Senior Action, 1990; nam_apap111-3.14_13 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Senior Action, June, September/October, 1991; nam_apap111-3.14_14 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Senior Action, January/February, July/August, 1992; nam_apap111-3.14_15 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Originals in New Format, nam_apap111-3.15
    - Senior Action, Winter, 1994; nam_apap111-3.15_1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Senior Action, Winter, Spring, Summer and "Special Edition", 1996; nam_apap111-3.15_2 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Senior Action, "Special Double Issue" December/January, February, April, May, September, October, 1997; nam_apap111-3.15_3 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Senior Action, May/June, September, 1998; nam_apap111-3.15_4 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Senior Action, April/May, August, "Special Edition", 1999; nam_apap111-3.15_5 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Senior Action, March, July/August, 2000; nam_apap111-3.15_6 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Senior Action Originals, nam_apap111-3.16
    - 1977 January-April, 1977 May-August; nam_apap111-3.16_1 (Oversize 3)
    - 1978 January-March, 1978 September-December; nam_apap111-3.16_2 (Oversize 3)
    - 1979, nam_apap111-3.16_3 (Oversize 3)
    - 1980 January, 1980 April-June; 1980 October; nam_apap111-3.16_4 (Oversize 3)
    - 1981 January-August, nam_apap111-3.16_5 (Oversize 3)
    - 1983, nam_apap111-3.16_6 (Oversize 3)
    - 1984, nam_apap111-3.16_7 (Oversize 3)
    - 1985, nam_apap111-3.16_8 (Oversize 4)
    - 1986, nam_apap111-3.16_9 (Oversize 4)
    - 1987, nam_apap111-3.16_10 (Oversize 4)
    - 1988, nam_apap111-3.16_11 (Oversize 4)
    - 1989, nam_apap111-3.16_12 (Oversize 4)
    - 1990, nam_apap111-3.16_13 (Oversize 4)
    - 1991 June, 1991 September-October; nam_apap111-3.16_14 (Oversize 4)
    - 1992 January-February, 1992 July-August; nam_apap111-3.16_15 (Oversize 4)
- Subject Files, 1974-1979; 1983-1999; nam_apap111-4; 9.58 cubic ft.
  These records, located within the following sub-series, comprise the base of information used by NYSSAC on issues important to senior citizens and NYSSAC's role as senior advocates.
  Arranged by subject
  - Health Care and Medicare, 1983-1998; nam_apap111-4.1; 6.79 cubic ft.
    These records, which constitute the bulk of the collection, consist of informational and issue files relating to health care topics affecting seniors in New York State. Significant topics addressed include Medicare, Medicaid, Medigap, Long-Term Care, Nursing Homes, DRG (Diagnosis-Related Groups), PROs (Peer-Review Organizations), HMO (Health Maintenance Organizations), the IPRO (Island Peer Review Organization), and others. Files hold information on state and federal health care legislation, the campaign for a national health care system in 1992-1993, the fight for prescription drug coverage for seniors in the state (EPIC) in 1986, and other issues. They include testimonies given before legislative bodies, reports, articles, booklets, legislative bulletins, memorandums, manuals, training material, and correspondence on various topics.
    - AARP Bulletin, 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - AARP PRONet, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - AARP Reports on PRO (Peer Review Organization) Reform, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - AARP Reports on PRO Reform, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Action for Primary Care Legislation, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Advocates for Medicare Assignment meeting, 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Alliance for Aging Research: Report on Home Care, Undated; nam_apap111-4.1_7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alzheimer's Disease, "Where to go For Help", NYC Department for the Aging, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Amsterdam Hospital Medicare Case, Information Packet, 1986; nam_apap111-4.1_9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Appointment of Dr. Mark Chassen, NY State Health Commissioner, 1991; nam_apap111-4.1_10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Assisted Living Position Paper, 1991; nam_apap111-4.1_11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Association of Area Agencies on the Aging, 1993; nam_apap111-4.1_12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Best Practices in Geriatric Care, 1994; nam_apap111-4.1_13 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Blue Cross/Blue Shield Rate Hike, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Blue Cross/Blue Shield Restructuring, 1999; nam_apap111-4.1_15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - BNA (Bureau of National Affairs) Health Care Policy Reports, 1996; nam_apap111-4.1_16 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Brookdale Foundation Medicaid File, Bulletins, 1988-1990; nam_apap111-4.1_17 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Brookdale Foundation Medicare File, Training Material, 1988-1989; nam_apap111-4.1_18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - California Medical Review: Premature Discharge Study, 1984-1986; nam_apap111-4.1_19 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - California Medical Review: Premature Discharge Study, Appendices, 1984-1986; nam_apap111-4.1_20 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - CALS (Community Action for Legal Services), 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_21 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Campaign for Quality and Choice in Managed Health Care, 1995; nam_apap111-4.1_22 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Campaign for Quality and Choice in Managed Health Care, 1995; nam_apap111-4.1_23 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Campaign for Quality and Choice in Managed Health Care, Copy of NY State Senate Bill 4188, 1995; nam_apap111-4.1_24 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Capital District Medical Consumers Association, Certificate of Incorporation, Undated; nam_apap111-4.1_25 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Capital District Senior Health Services Bureau, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_26 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Capital District Senior Health Services Bureau, 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_27 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Center for Medicare Advocacy Waiver of Liability, 1996; nam_apap111-4.1_28 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - CHCF (Council on Health Care Financing), 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_29 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - CHCF Health Planning Study, Presentations and Staff Report, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_30 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - CHCF Health Planning Study, Profiles and By-laws of Health Systems Agencies, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_31 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - CHIC (Consumer Health Information Center) Nursing Home Directory, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_32 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Children's Health Care Campaign, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_33 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Children's Health Plan (CHP) and Pre-need Materials, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_34 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Coalition for Primary Care Legislation, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_35 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Coalition to Save Home Care, 1991; nam_apap111-4.1_36 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Coalition to Save Medicare, 1995-1996; nam_apap111-4.1_37 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Cobble Hill Nursing Home vs. Henry & Warren Corp., Amici Curiae Brief by NY Lawyers for the Public Interest, 1985-1989; nam_apap111-4.1_38 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - COBRA Health Insurance, 1986; nam_apap111-4.1_39 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Committee for Injured Infants' Rights, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_40 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Committee for Quality Health Care, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_41 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Committee for Quality Health Care, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_42 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Committee for Quality Health Care, 1993-1994; nam_apap111-4.1_43 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Congressional Candidate Medicare Surveys, 1998; nam_apap111-4.1_44 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Consumer Advocates' Meeting with Mark Chassen, 1991; nam_apap111-4.1_45 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Consumer Choice Alliance for Long Term Care, Draft, ca. 1994; nam_apap111-4.1_46 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Department of Health, "Do Not Resuscitate" Guidelines, Undated; nam_apap111-4.1_47 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Department of Health, Health Care Financing Administration, Guidelines and Forms, 1986-1987; nam_apap111-4.1_48 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Department of Health, Health Care Financing Administration, Guidelines and Forms, 1988-1989; nam_apap111-4.1_49 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Department of Health, Hospital Code Amendments, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_50 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Department of Health, Hospital Code Guidelines, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_51 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Department of Health, Memo on Health Facilities, 1987; nam_apap111-4.1_52 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Department of Health, Memos on Mandatory Medicare Assignment, 1991; nam_apap111-4.1_53 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Department of Health, Task Force on Long-Term Care Financing, Public Hearing, 1996; nam_apap111-4.1_54 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Department of Health, Task Force on Long-Term Care Financing, Public Hearing Testimonies, 1996; nam_apap111-4.1_55 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Department of Social Services Directive on Treatment of Medicaid Trust Funding, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_56 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Directory of Adult Care Facilities in NYS, 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_57 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Discharge Planning, News Clippings, 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_58 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Discretionary Trust Packet, "Take Me to Your Lawyer", for Families of the Disabled, 1991; nam_apap111-4.1_59 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - DRG (Diagnosis Related Groups) Action Information, 1985-1987; nam_apap111-4.1_60 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - DRG Action Information, 1985-1987; nam_apap111-4.1_61 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - DRG News Clippings, 1987; nam_apap111-4.1_62 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - DRG Discharge Review Planning, 1990; nam_apap111-4.1_63 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    - DRG Discharge Studies, 1987; nam_apap111-4.1_64 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - DRG Education Project, 1990; nam_apap111-4.1_65 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - DRG Monitoring Committee, 1987; nam_apap111-4.1_66 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - DRG/PPS (Prospective Payment System) Action Material, 1986-1987; nam_apap111-4.1_67 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - DRG/PPS News Clippings and Reports, 1985-1986; nam_apap111-4.1_68 (Box 2, Folder 23-25)
    - DRG/PPS Cases, 1986-1987; nam_apap111-4.1_69 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - DRG/PPS Cases and Testimony, 1986; nam_apap111-4.1_70 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - DRG Steering Committee, 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_71 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - DRG Strategy Group, 1989-1990; nam_apap111-4.1_72 (Box 2, Folder 29-31)
    - DRG Strategy Group, Legal Support Unit Memos, 1983-1986; nam_apap111-4.1_73 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - DRG Strategy Group, Legal Support Unit Memos, 1987-1988; nam_apap111-4.1_74 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - DRG Supporting Publications, 1989-1995; nam_apap111-4.1_75 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - DRG Training Manual, 1986; nam_apap111-4.1_76 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Eastern Paralyzed Veteran's Association Summit, 1995; nam_apap111-4.1_77 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - EISEP (Expanded In-home Services for the Elderly Program) Information, 1987-1990; nam_apap111-4.1_78 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Empire Blue Cross/Blue Shield Rate Filing Narrative Summary, 1995; nam_apap111-4.1_79 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Empire Blue Cross/Blue Shield Rate Increase Legislation, 1995; nam_apap111-4.1_80 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Empire State Medical, Scientific and Educational Foundation Advisory Committee, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_81 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - EPIC (Elderly Pharmaceutical Insurance Coverage Program) Advisory Committee, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_82 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - EPIC, Information Packets, 1986; nam_apap111-4.1_83 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - EPIC, Legislation, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_84 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - ERISA (Employee Retirement Income Security Act), Preemption, 1993; nam_apap111-4.1_85 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Family and Medical Leave Act, 1991; nam_apap111-4.1_86 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Friends and Relatives of the Institutionalized Aged (FRIA), 1990; nam_apap111-4.1_87 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Governor Cuomo's Health Care Message, 1993; nam_apap111-4.1_88 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Governor Cuomo's Revised Long Term Care Access Bill, 153R, 1994; nam_apap111-4.1_89 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Governors' Association (National Governors' Association) Proposal on Medicaid, 1996; nam_apap111-4.1_90 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Greater New York Hospital Association Memo, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_91 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - HCFA (Health Care Financing Administration) Medicare Publications, 1995; nam_apap111-4.1_92 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - HCFA Policy Correspondence, 1987; nam_apap111-4.1_93 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Health Care Agents and Proxies Bill #76 RR, 1990; nam_apap111-4.1_94 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Health Care Campaign Surveys, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_95 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Health Care News Clippings, 1991; nam_apap111-4.1_96 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Health Care News Clippings, 1996; nam_apap111-4.1_97 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Health Care For All, Advocacy Group, 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_98 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Health Care For All, Bulletins and Background Material, 1988-1991; nam_apap111-4.1_99 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Health Care For All, Campaign, 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_100 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Health Care For All, Campaign, 1993; nam_apap111-4.1_101 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Health Care For All, Campaign Structure, 1991; nam_apap111-4.1_102 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Health Care For All, Meeting, 1994; nam_apap111-4.1_103 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Health Care For All, Patients' Rights Fund, 1993; nam_apap111-4.1_104 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Health Care Reform, 1993; nam_apap111-4.1_105 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Health Care Reform, 1994; nam_apap111-4.1_106 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Health Care Reform Debate, 1992-1993; nam_apap111-4.1_107 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Health Care Reform, Legislative Action Materials, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_108 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Health Care Surveillance Work Group, 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_109 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Health Data Design Committee, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_110 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Health Financing Advisory Group, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_111 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Health Issues File, 1987; nam_apap111-4.1_112 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Health Systems Agencies Information, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_113 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Hearing Aid Dispensing, Assembly Bill 1175A, 1995; nam_apap111-4.1_114 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Hearing Aid Legislation, 1995-1996; nam_apap111-4.1_115 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Hill-Burton Program Information, 1985-1988; nam_apap111-4.1_116 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - HMO (Heath Maintenance Organization) Community Ratings, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_117 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Home Care Assessment Tool, (HARRI), 1993; nam_apap111-4.1_118 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Home Care for the Functionally Impaired, 1986; nam_apap111-4.1_119 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Hospital Admissions Information, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_120 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Hospital Association of NY, Report, 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_121 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Hospital Information, 1986-1989; nam_apap111-4.1_122 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Hospital Patient Rights, 1994; nam_apap111-4.1_123 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - "How to Talk About Health Care", Arnold Bennett, 1990; nam_apap111-4.1_124 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Human Services Summit, 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_125 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - IPRO (Island Peer Review Organization) Committee Meetings, 1990; nam_apap111-4.1_126 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - IPRO, DRG Strategy Group, 1990; nam_apap111-4.1_127 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - IPRO Medicare Administrative Memos, 1990; nam_apap111-4.1_128 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - IPRO Medicare Administrative Memos, 1992-1993; nam_apap111-4.1_129 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - IPRO Outreach, 1991; nam_apap111-4.1_130 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - IPRO Problems/Complaints, 1990; nam_apap111-4.1_131 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Legal Services for the Elderly, Medicaid/Home Care, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_132 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Letter From National Council of Senior Citizens, Undated; nam_apap111-4.1_133 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Long Term Care Access, 1992-1993; nam_apap111-4.1_134 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Long Term Care Access, 1994; nam_apap111-4.1_135 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Long Term Care Access Reform, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_136 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Long Term Care Access Reform, 1993; nam_apap111-4.1_137 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Long Term Care Access Reform, 1994; nam_apap111-4.1_138 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Long Term Care Access Reform, Support Material, 1993; nam_apap111-4.1_139 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Long Term Care Access, Task Force, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_140 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Long Term Care Alliance Mailing Lists, 1994; nam_apap111-4.1_141 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Long Term Care Assessment Consolidation Project, 1993; nam_apap111-4.1_142 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Long Term Care Assessment Seminar, Transcript, 1994; nam_apap111-4.1_143 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Long Term Care Campaign, 1988; nam_apap111-4.1_144 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Long Term Care Campaign, 1990; nam_apap111-4.1_145 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Long Term Care Campaign Action, 1989-1991; nam_apap111-4.1_146 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Long Term Care Campaign, Correspondence to Governor Guidelines, Undated; nam_apap111-4.1_147 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Long Term Care Information, 1990-1994; nam_apap111-4.1_148 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Long Term Care Initiatives in Massachusetts and New Jersey, 1994; nam_apap111-4.1_149 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Long Term Care Insurance News Clipping, 1993; nam_apap111-4.1_150 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Long Term Care Public Policy Issues, 1992-1994; nam_apap111-4.1_151 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Long Term Care Reform Conference, 1994; nam_apap111-4.1_152 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Long Term Care Services, 1993; nam_apap111-4.1_153 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Long Term Care Single Payer Plan Reform, 1991-1992; nam_apap111-4.1_154 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Long Term Care Strategic Development Committee, 1995; nam_apap111-4.1_155 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Managed Access to Aging Services (MAAS) Proposal, 1991; nam_apap111-4.1_156 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Mandatory Medicare Assignment, Bill A. 3500, 1990; nam_apap111-4.1_157 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Mandatory Medicare Assignment, Bill A. 3500, 1991; nam_apap111-4.1_158 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Mandatory Medicare Assignment, Bill A. 12304, NYS Supreme Court Case, 1992; nam_apap111-4.1_159 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Mandatory Medicare Assignment Campaign, 1987-1988; nam_apap111-4.1_160 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Mandatory Medicare Assignment Campaign, 1988-1990; nam_apap111-4.1_161 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Mandatory Medicare Assignment Campaign, 1990; nam_apap111-4.1_162 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Mandatory Medicare Assignment Enforcement, 1989-1990; nam_apap111-4.1_163 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Mandatory Medicare Assignment Public Hearings, 1987; nam_apap111-4.1_164 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Mandatory Medicare Assignment Public Response, 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_165 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Massachusetts Health Care Legislation, 1987; nam_apap111-4.1_166 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - "Medicaid: A Program Crucial to Women's Health", National Women's Law Center, ca. 1995; nam_apap111-4.1_167 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Medicaid Applications by County, 1989; nam_apap111-4.1_168 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Medicaid Application Guide, 1985; nam_apap111-4.1_169 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Medicaid, Bill 328, Home Care Provisions, 1996; nam_apap111-4.1_170 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Medicaid Block Grant, 1995; nam_apap111-4.1_171 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Medicaid Block Grant, Material, 1995; nam_apap111-4.1_172 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Medicaid Cuts, 1994-1995; nam_apap111-4.1_173 (Box 5, Folder 3)